Guide to the Propaganda Poster Collection 1914-1996
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
- Series 2: Propaganda Posters (United States),World War I, circa 1914-1920
  - Subseries 2.1: Food Conservation and Material Donations, 1914-1919
    - Sugar Means Ships, circa 1917; English; 48.5 x 39.5 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. Printed by Carey Printing Company, New York. (Folder 11, Item 45)
      Urges the American public to reduce consumption of sugary beverages, because the transportation of sugar diverts ships from the war effort. The graphic image depicts a woman drinking from a straw connected to the ocean, pulling ships from the other side o
    - Little Americans: Do Your Bit, circa 1917-1918; English;; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. (Folder 11, Item 46)
      Encourages children to eat corn and rice based cereals, saving wheat for soldiers. Graphic depicts a small boy saluting a bowl of oatmeal. (2 copies)
    - Use More Potatoes, circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 70 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. Food Committee State Council of Defense. Federal Food Administrator for Washington. (Folder 11, Item 47)
      Poster aimed at encouraging the use of potatoes over wheat-based products by listing the potato's attributes.
    - Corn: The Food of the Nation, 1918; English; 53.5 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Lloyd Harrison. United States Food Administration. Printed by Landauer Inc., Baltimore. (Folder 11, Item 48)
      Depicts woman cooking with corn products to demonstrate the many uses of corn for preparing meals in place of wheat. (2 copies)
    - Boys! Serve Your Country, circa 1914-1918; English; 27.5 x 18 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Issued by the Boys' Working Reserve, U.S.A. (Folder 12, Item 49)
      Encourages American boys to serve their country on the farms by joining the U.S. Boys' Working Reserve. Graphic shows a farmer plowing farmland behind a horse. (2 copies)
    - Keep the Home Garden Going, 1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: William McKee. United States Food Administration. Printed by Forbes, Boston. (Folder 12, Item 50)
      Depicts three farmers, laden with crops, in order to encourage citizens to continue growing crops to help the war effort. (2 copies)
    - You Also Can Help Solve the Meat Problem, circa 1914-1918; English; 39.5 x 54.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Louis Moen. Printed by the Red Wing Advertising Company. (Folder 12, Item 51)
      Encourages individuals to salt and cure their own meats in stoneware jars. Picture shows a woman labeled "Patriot" carrying cured meats and walking among stoneware jars. (2 copies)
    - Food Will Win the War, circa 1918; English; 50.5 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. Printed by Rusling Wood Litho., New York. (Folder 13, Item 52)
      Specifically targets immigrants who came to America, encouraging them to preserve the freedom they sought. Calls for waste minimization, and mentions wheat as one of the most needed crops. Image shows immigrants sailing into New York Harbor, with the city
    - Keep It Coming, circa 1918; English; 53 x 73 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: George Illian. United States Food Administration. Printed by The W.F. Powers Company, New York. (Folder 13, Item 53)
      Stresses the importance of sending food to the front lines, not just for the soldiers, but also for the women and children behind the lines. Poster includes a quote from General John J. Pershing. Picture shows convoy of army trucks filled with food. (2 co
    - Feed a Fighter, circa 1914-1918; English; 53.5 x 74 cm. Primarily black and white with "Waste Nothing" in red print.; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. Printed by The Strobridge Lithograph Company, Cincinnati and New York. (Folder 13, Item 54)
      Discourages waste to allow more resources for soldiers and their families. Graphic is a reproduction charcoal sketch of a soldier drinking coffee in the trenches. (2 copies)
    - Beat Germany, 1917; English; 35.5 x 54.5. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Adolph Treidler. United States Food Administration. Printed by Heywood Strasser & Voigt Litho. Co., New York. (Folder 14, Item 55)
      Encourages the support of any nation opposing Prussianism through food conservation and donations. Graphic shows armed soldiers carrying the flags of the United States, United Kingdom, France, which are covering the Italian and German flags. (2 copies)
    - Cardinal Mercier, circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Printed by Latham Lithograph and Printing Company, Brooklyn, New York. (Folder 14, Item 56)
      Relays Cardinal Mercier's appeal to the Food Administration for more food for war victims. Encourages food conservation to allow for more donations to France, Belgium, and Italy. (2 copies)
    - They Are Giving All, 1918; English; 140 x 91 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Harvey Dunn. U.S. Food Administration. Printed by The W.F. Powers Company, New York. (Folder 14, Item 57)
      Poster asserting the soldiers' need for wheat. Graphic shows a battle scene. (2 copies)
    - Save and Serve the Cause of Freedom, circa 1914-1918; English; 52.5 x 73 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. Printed by the W.F. Powers Company, New York. (Folder 15, Item 58)
      Poster offers a four-part list of foods to conserve, and gives conservation-friendly alternatives.
    - Food: Don't Waste It, circa 1914-1918; English; 52.5 x 73 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: United States Food Administration. Printed by The W.F. Powers Company, New York. (Folder 15, Item 59)
      Poster lists six ways to conserve food. (2 copies)
    - Food Control is a War Measure, circa 1914-1918; English; 64 x 97 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 15, Item 60)
      Poster outlining the Allied strategy for the food conservation campaign, emphasizing the point that the army's needs always come first. (2 copies)
    - Why Loyal Americans are Keeping the Pledge, circa 1917-1919; English; 50.5 x 75 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 15, Item 61)
      Poster informing the general public of the reasons why avoiding the consumption of wheat and meat is vital to ensure the steady flow of supplies to our troops and allies in war torn Europe.
    - The President Says, circa 1914-1918; English; 53 x 28 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Adolph Treidler. U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 16, Item 62)
      Offers a quotation from President Wilson that reads, "Hunger does not breed reform; it breeds madness and all the ugly distemper that makes ordered life impossible...The future belongs to those who prove themselves the true friends of mankind." A pastel por
    - Do Not Be Fooled by the Lies of the Enemy, circa 1914-1918; English; 35.5 x 55.5 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 16, Item 63)
      This bulletin assures the public that the U.S. government has no intention of seizing private food reserves from its citizens, but reminds that hoarding of food or collecting more than is reasonable or necessary, is morally wrong and detrimental to the wa
    - War Rages in France, circa 1914-1918; English; 50.5 x 75.5 cm. Black and white.; Creator/Publisher: Frederick Henry Townsend. U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 16, Item 64)
      Picture of hungry people crowded in the streets of France to illustrate the need for U.S. citizens to conserve food in support of the war effort. (2 copies)
    - Will You Help the Women of France?, 1918; English; 140 x 92 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Edward Penfield. U.S. Food Administration. Printed by The W.F. Powers Company, New York. (Folder 16, Item 65)
      Picture shows three women laboring with farm equipment. Poster serves as a reminder that the women of France are feeding themselves, their children and also their soldiers, and encourages Americans to save wheat. (2 copies)
    - Victory is a Question of Stamina, 1917; English; 53 x 72.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Harvey Dunn. U.S. Food Administration. Printed by Latham Lithography and Printing, Brooklyn, N.Y. (Folder 17, Item 66)
      Graphic showing soldiers advancing on the battlefield with the slogan: "Victory is a Question of Stamina." Poster encourages the public to send more wheat, meat, fats, and sugar, the alleged "fuel for fighters."
    - Sir, Don't Waste, circa 1917; English; 53 x 73.5 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Crawford Young. U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 17, Item 67)
      Poster encouraging public not to waste food and adopt a "clean plate" doctrine. Graphic shows a rich gentleman leaving a large amount of food on his plate.
    - Blood or Bread, 1917; English; 53 x 73.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. Printed by Forbes, Boston. (Folder 17, Item 68)
      Anti-waste poster. Graphic is a reproduced pastel drawing depicting a soldier carrying a fallen comrade. (2 copies)
    - Save Food and Defeat Frightfulness, circa 1918; English; 141 x 92 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Herbert Paus. Printed by The Strobridge Lithograph Company, Cincinnati and New York. (Folder 17, Item 69)
      Reminder issued by the United States Food Administration to conserve supplies. Features a quote: "America: the hope of all who suffer, the dread of all who wrong." Image shows wounded war victims pointing to the quote.
    - Eat More, Eat Less, circa 1917; English; 53 x 73 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: U.S. Food Administration. Printed by Heywood, Strasser & Voigt Lithograph Company, New York. (Folder 18, Item 70)
      Lists the appropriate foods to eat, as well as the foods to be conserved for the war effort. Image shows a table covered in approved foods, such as fish, fruits and vegetables. (2 copies)
    - This Is What God Gives Us, circa 1917; English; 53 x 73.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: A. Hendee. U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 18, Item 71)
      Poster showing graphic of storehouse filled with fresh produce with the message: "This is what GOD gave us. What are you giving so that others may live? Eat less wheat, meat, fats, sugar. Send more to Europe or they will starve."
    - Save the Products of the Land, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Charles Livingston Bull. U.S. Food Administration. (Folder 18, Item 72)
      Poster showing images of fish swimming to reinforce the suggestion of eating more fish to help conserve meat for the soldiers.
  - Subseries 2.2: Financial Aid: War Savings Stamps, 1914-1918
    - Joan of Arc Saved France, 1918; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Haskell Coffin. United States Treasury Department. (Folder 19, Item 73)
      Part of an ad campaign to boost sales of war savings stamps, this poster shows an image of Joan of Arc to inspire the public to fund the war effort.
    - Keep Him Free, 1917; English; 50 x 75 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Charles Livingston Bull. United States Treasury Department. Stamped by the Committee on Public Information, Division of Pictorial Publicity. Printed at Ketterlinus, Phila. (Folder 19, Item 74)
      Advertisement for War Savings Stamps. Graphic shows a bald eagle towering over a nest with hangars inside and allied airplanes flying out to do battle.
    - They Give Their Lives, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 76 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: H. Devitt Welsh. Printed by Sackett & Wilhelms Corp. N.Y. Issued by the Committee on Public Information Division of Pictorial Publicity and the United States Government. (Folder 19, Item 75)
      Poster encouraging the public to lend their savings to the war effort by buying war savings stamps. Graphic shows a gloomy hilltop with crosses arranged so as to be reminiscent of the crucifixion.
    - Help Them, Keep Your War Savings Pledge, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Casper Emerson Jr. Issued by U.S. Treasury Department. Printed by American Lithographic Co. N.Y. (Folder 19, Item 76)
      Graphic showing war savings stamps being fed into a machine gun to persuade American citizens that their investment in war savings stamps will help win the war.
    - Share in the Victory, 1918; English; 49.5 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Haskell Coffin. Published by Rusling Wood, Mural Advertising. (Folder 19, Item 77)
      Graphic depicting an angelic being holding a sword and a palm frond with the message, "Share in the Victory, Save for Your Country, Save for Yourself, Buy War Savings Stamps."
    - Save Your Child, 1918; English; 71 x 97 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Herbert Paus. Issued by the United States Treasury Department. Printed by the United States Printing and Lithograph Co. N.Y. (Folder 19, Item 78)
      Image of small child holding the torch hand of the statue of liberty with the message that buying war savings stamps will save children from "autocracy and poverty."
  - Subseries 2.3: Financial Aid: Red Cross, 1914-1918
    - Ten Million Dollars a Year, circa 1914-1918; English; 50 x 75.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Red Cross. Printed by American Lithographic Co. N.Y. (Folder 20, Item 79)
      A poster for the Red Cross annual roll call to raise money for the disabled ex-service men and their families.
    - The First Three, circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 70 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Kidder. Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 20, Item 80)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross featuring the first three American soldiers to die in the war, by name: Hay, Enright, and Gresham. Produced for War Fund Week, it advertises the need to raise one hundred million dollars. (2 copies)
    - While Someone Gives His Life.., circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 69.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 20, Item 81)
      Red Cross fundraising poster reminding the public that "All of the Red Cross War Fund goes for War Relief."
    - Think What You Can Afford To Give.., circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 69.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 20, Item 82)
    - If You Knew.., circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 69.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 20, Item 83)
    - Help the Red Cross, circa 1914-1918; English; 48 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Herman Roeg. Red Cross. (Folder 20, Item 84)
      Red Cross promotional poster depicting a nurse holding an injured soldier with free arm raised high. (2 copies)
    - Caring for American Soldiers in England, 1918; English; 35.5 x 53 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: War Council of the American Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 85)
      A bulletin issued by the Red Cross to inform the American public how their donations have gone to help soldiers overseas. Graphic depicts an American soldier strolling from a busy London square.
    - American Prisoners of War Cared for by the Red Cross, circa 1917-1918; English; 35.5 x 53 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: War Council of the American Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 86)
      A bulletin issued by the Red Cross to inform the American public how their donations have gone to help prisoners of war in German prison camps. Near the bottom are instructions on how to send Christmas parcels to prisoners of war.
    - Hold Up Your End!, 1917; English; 52 x 69.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: W. B. King. Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 21, Item 87)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross featuring an image of a concerned Red Cross nurse holding one end of a stretcher with a bomb exploding in the background.
    - The Roll Call, A Masque of the Red Cross, circa 1914-1918; English; 48 x 79.5 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Arnold Genthe. Percy Mac Kaye. Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 88)
      A poster advertising the Red Cross. Graphic shows a heavily shadowed statue reaching for the Red Cross symbol. (2 copies)
    - Motherless, Fatherless, Starving, circa 1914-1918; English; 52 x 69 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Crisp. Red Cross. Second War Fund. (Folder 21, Item 89)
      Red Cross promotional poster advertising "War Fund Week, One Hundred Million Dollars, May 20-27." Graphic depicts a Red Cross nurse caring for a group of French children outside a burning city. (2 copies)
    - Universal Membership Week, circa 1914-1918; English; 106 x 21.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Harrison Fisher. A. Foringer. Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 90)
      Poster utilizing the work of two well-known artists to advertise for the annual Christmas roll call of the Red Cross.
    - Is There a Red Cross Service Flag in Your Home?, 1917; English; 140 x 90.5 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Seiter & Kappes Lithography Co. New York. Copyright by Wells Fargo & Company. Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 91)
      A message from the Red Cross stating that "a heart and a dollar" is all someone needs to join the Red Cross.
    - They Fight For You, circa 1914-1918; English; 71.5 x 104 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: W.G. Sesser. Latham Lithography and Printing Co. Red Cross. (Folder 21, Item 92)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross. Graphic shows the Statue of Liberty, holding the Red Cross Shield, rising above a soldier wounded on the battlefield. (2 copies)
    - Are You One of Us?, 1917; English; 141 x 88 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: L. N. Britton. Latham Lithography and Printing Co. Red Cross. (Folder 22, Item 93)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross War Fund. Graphic shows a group of soldiers, women and children looking to a large Red Cross beacon looming over the Capital Building and the Statue of Liberty.
    - Red Cross Christmas Roll Call, 1918; English; 142 x 214 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: E. H. Blashfield. (Folder 22, Item 94)
      Advertisement for the Red Cross Christmas Roll Call. Graphic shows a Red Cross nurse holding a scroll, and another woman signing it. The scroll reads, "Where Columbia Sets Her Name Let Everyone of You Follow Her."
    - Have You Answered the Red Cross Christmas Roll Call?, 1918; English; 70 x 74 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Harrison Fisher. American National Red Cross. (Folder 23, Item 95)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross War Fund. Graphic shows a Red Cross nurse reaching toward the audience with a beckoning expression while troops march by in the background.
    - If You Can't Go Across With A Gun.., 1917; English; 71.5 x 105 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: C. W. Love. The United States Printing & Lithography. Red Cross. (Folder 23, Item 96)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross War Fund. Graphic shows a wounded soldier, a woman, and a child looking across the water toward a city line and the Statue of Liberty. Red Cross symbol is in the top left corner. (2 copies)
    - We Need You, 1918; English; 77 x 100 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Albert Sterner. American Lithographic Co. N.Y. Red Cross. (Folder 23, Item 97)
      Recruiting poster for the Red Cross. Graphic shows one nurse, with her arm around a regularly clothed woman, pointing as another nurse tends to an injured man.
    - What are YOU Doing to Help?, circa 1914-1918; English; 63 x 96 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Gordon Grant. Red Cross. (Folder 23, Item 98)
      Recruitment poster for the American Red Cross. Graphic is a reproduction of a charcoal drawing depicting a uniformed nurse leading a bandaged soldier.
    - What Can You Do?, circa 1914-1918; English; 70 x 106 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Red Cross. (Folder 23, Item 99)
      Recruitment poster for the Red Cross. Graphic background is a large red cross, in front of which a Red Cross nurse tends to a wounded soldier, and a mother and her children.
    - Keep this Hand of Mercy at its Work, circa 1914-1918; English; 51.5 x 69 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: P.G. Morgan. Red Cross. (Folder 24, Item 100)
      Fundraising poster for the Red Cross War Fund Week. Graphic shows a hand clothed in a Red Cross uniform sleeve reaching down and sheltering the poor and wounded from the violent explosions on the battlefield.
    - Put Fighting Blood In Your Business, circa 1920; English; 70.5 x 48 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Dan Smith. Quote by Arthur Woods, Assistant to the Secretary of War. American Red Cross. The Department of War. The Department of Labor. Designed and printed by Thomsen-Ellis Company: Baltimore and New York. (Folder 24, Item 101)
      Poster used as part of an ad campaign to bring job security to World War I veterans. Graphic depicts American soldiers charging into battle with a list of French cities written on a golden emblem. The written message encourages businesses to list their em
    - I Summon You to the Comradeship, 1918; English; 51 x 70 cm. Black and white with Red Cross symbol.; Creator/Publisher: Leo M. Mielziner. Quote by Woodrow Wilson. Red Cross. U.S. Printing and Lithography Co. N.Y. (Folder 24, Item 102)
      Ad poster for the Red Cross with an endorsement from President Wilson to answer the Red Cross Christmas Roll Call for Universal Membership. (2 copies)
    - Have YOU a Red Cross Service Flag?, 1918; English; 53 x 71 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Jessie Willcox Smith. American Red Cross. Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 24, Item 103)
      Graphic shows a child, seated at a window while pasting a Red Cross service flag in the middle pane. (2 copies)
    - It is a Remarkable Story, circa 1918; English; 35.5 x 53 cm. Black and white with red accents.; Creator/Publisher: Woodrow Wilson. Red Cross. (Folder 24, Item 104)
      Bulletin No. 5 issued by the War Council of the American Red Cross to tell the story of Red Cross activities to the American people. (2 copies)
    - The Greatest Mother in the World (Small Version), 1918; English; 52 x 70 cm. Sepia with Red Cross symbol.; Creator/Publisher: A. E. Foringer. American National Red Cross. Form N.Y. 31 Second War Fund. (Folder 24, Item 105)
      Red Cross poster depicting a wounded soldier, bandaged and on a stretcher, being cradled by a Red Cross Nurse.
    - The Greatest Mother in the World, 1918; English; 69.5 x 106 cm. Sepia with Red Cross symbol.; Creator/Publisher: A. E. Foringer. American National Red Cross. Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 24, Item 106)
      Poster for the Red Cross Christmas Roll Call. Depicts a wounded soldier, bandaged and on a stretcher, being cradled by a Red Cross Nurse. (2 copies)
  - Subseries 2.4: Financial Aid: War Bonds, 1914-1919
    - Americans All!, 1919; English; 68 x 101 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Howard Chandler Christy. Forbes, Boston. (Folder 25, Item 107)
      Advertisement for Victory Liberty Loan. Graphic shows a woman in Grecian dress holding a laurel wreath over the "Honor Roll" which lists surnames with obviously ethnic origins. The U.S. flag is in the background.
    - For Home and Country, 1918; English; 74.5 x 101 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Alfred Everitt Orr. (Folder 25, Item 108)
      Advertisement for Victory Liberty Loan. Graphic depicts a soldier embracing his wife and child.
    - Sure! We'll Finish the Job, 1918; English; 66 x 96 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Gerrit A. Beneker. Edwards & Deutsch Lithograph Company, Chicago. (Folder 25, Item 109)
      Advertisement for Victory Liberty Loan depicting a smiling man in overalls, probably a farmer.
    - And They Thought We Couldn't Fight, circa 1918; English; 76.5 x 103 cm. Color.; Creator/Publisher: Clyde Forsythe. Ketterlinus, Philadelphia. (Folder 25, Item 110)